# **AJITH PG**

# Front End Developer

### **SUMMARY**

Passionate Front End Developer with 3+ years of experience in developing web applications. Skilled at writing clear, concise code that is easy to maintain and troubleshoot. Experienced in working with both small and large teams across multiple projects and companies. Able to work independently of remote locations or in office environments as needed by the company.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Front End Developer

05/2021 - Present

### Tata Consultancy Services (TCS)

Kochi, Kerala

- Worked collaboratively with clients and the project team to conceptualize, design, and implement new features, aligning the user interface with client expectations and project requirements
- Successfully implemented branch-specific requirements for banking applications, enhancing the application's functionality to meet the diverse needs of individual branches.
- Automated the entire application using the UFT Automation Tool for defect-free delivery of code
- Utilized agile methodologies to enhance project flexibility and responsiveness to evolving branch requirements

UI Developer 06/2020 - 04/2021

GL Infotech Thrissur, Kerala

- Developed 5+ websites of all sorts: e- Ecommerce, hospitals, CMS sites, and food products
- Implemented SEO best practices during the development process, contributing to improved website rankings on search engines.
- Enhance website performance, optimizing code and assets for faster load times, resulting in improved user satisfaction.
- Led the conversion of UI designs from scratch for E-commerce and CMS sites, translating conceptual designs into functional HTML, CSS, and JavaScript code.

Web Developer

12/2019 - 05/2020

# i-Techtonic Systems

Coimbatore, TamilNadu

- Developed its own website from scratch to get customers and an online presence.
- Optimized website performance and SEO
- Developed a website for an Agriculture based food products company to increase their online presence and sales

### **EDUCATION**

B.Tech: Computer Science and Engineering

APJ Abdul Kalam Technological University

Kerala,India

Higher Secondary, Computer Science

Kerala State Board

Kerala, India

### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

# Build a Web Application for Early Stage Startup

Developed a web application for a STEM-based startup called Holbos, which helped them gain customers across countries.

Link:<u>www</u>.holbos.com">https://undefine d.holbos.com

#### Branch-Centric Customization

Branch-specific requirements for banking application, enhancing the application's functionality to meet the diverse needs of individual branches.

### Performance Optimization:

Applied performance tuning techniques to optimize the application's speed and responsiveness of 3+ e-commerce websites

## Improved Business

Developed a website for an Agriculture based food products company to increase their online presence and sales

### **SKILLS**

### JS Framework

React · Redux

## Web Technologies

Javascript · HTML · CSS · Jquery ·

Tailwind CSS · UFT Automation ·

 $\mathsf{Material}\;\mathsf{UI}\cdot\mathsf{Bootstrap}\cdot\mathsf{SASS}\cdot\mathsf{Git}$ 

### **Design Tools**

Figma · Adobe XD

# **PROFILES**

★ Linkedin

http://www.linkedin.com/in/ajith-pg

https://github.com/AjithPG